如果希望你的app的 content provider
It's actually quite straightforward
被第三方的apps能够使用，其实是
to make your apps content provider
很容易的。
available to third party apps.
关键就是要把manifest 文件里 export 参数值
The key is to modify the export flag
设置成"true"。
in the manifest entry here to "true".
zai简单不过了。
As simple as that.
任何一个知道 content URI 的 app,
Any app that knows the content URI,
都可以使用 content 来
can use the content resolve
让你访问这些内容.
would access it
the same way that you do.
现在由于你的app里数据的敏感程度，
Now depending on
the sensitivity of your data,
你需要保护数据，通过设置一个
you may want to protect it
访问允许值。
by requiring specific permissions
从而可以读写这些数据。
to read or write to the database.
这样，就可以有效的限制
So if you want to, you can
你的数据访问者。
effectively limit access
只有那些你自己创建的app,或者是
only to other apps you've created,
一些有访问权限的第三方apps
or to third party apps
才能够被允许来访问你的app
which know the permissions
and users agree to.
然后你只需要发布一下
Then you just need
这个访问合约
to publish this contract
这样可以让content provider 和 URI 互动
to interact with the content provider,
特别注意的是URI 和 column 的名字。
specifically the URI and column names.
这样你已经创建了一个简单的API
And you've created a simple API
来为你的app 数据。
for all of your data.
就是这么简单，你创建了新的
And as simple as that,
API，
you've created a new API,
来支持你的数据访问。
just for your data.
这个解决方案呢恰恰是被
This is exactly the same approach
许多本地的content provider 使用的，
used by many of the
native content providers,
这些数据包括了联系人数据，
including the Contacts Database,
媒体库，日历和呼叫日志。
Media Store, Calendar and Call Log.